

JOSEPH HODGES

Software Engineer | AI/ML | DevOps | Python

hephxtus

@ joe.hodges2000@gmail.com

> +64 021 023 93440

hephxtus.github.io

Wellington, NZ

STRENGTHS

AI/ML

Cybersecurity

DevOps | Virtualisation

Linux | Agile | CI/CD

Red Hat

Software Design

VCS

Fast learner

Persistence

Prioritisation

Teamwork

Communication skills

Seek out Feedback

Goal Oriented

LEARNING

AWS

Docker

Networking

Cloud

Generative Al

Mobile Development

LANGUAGES

Proficient: Python | Bash | Java **Experienced:** Ansible | SQL | C++ | C# Familiar: Go | Ruby | F# | JS/TS

Frameworks: Flutter | React | .NET

ABOUT ME

in joe-hodges

Software Engineer specialising in AI/ML and Full Stack Development with 2 years industry experience looking for next challenge. Motivated and eager to learn with experience at all stages of the software development lifecycle.

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer | NZX

11 2021 - Now

Wellington, NZ

- Designed, Implemented and Supported Automated Deployment scripts in python and ansible for applications and frameworks
- Developed CI/CD pipelines with Github Actions to ensure code quality organisation
- Re-architect, Deployment and Maintenance of Tier One Legacy Systems across the organisation and stack.
- Oracle and Postgres Database Migration and deployment
- Assisted in training and upskilling new graduates

Junior Developer | Qontro

1 02 2021 - 11 2021

Auckland, NZ

- Brought in at the start of the year to rebuild their helpdesk (migrating to a freshdesk system), which involved writing an internal API in python as well as CLI to interact
- Through personnel changes I became the defacto project manager and successfully saw this project through to handover.
- Briefed new project managers on progress, as well as giving regular updates to the wider company and CEO.
- Interfaced with Enterprise software, RESTful APIs, and python development
- Gained familiarity with Agile environments, Jira, and Confluence

ECS Outreach programme | Victoria University of Wellington

1 03 2020 - 11 2021

Auckland, NZ

- Mentorship of more first and second year Computer Science/Software Engineering Students
- Representing the Engineering faculty at events around Wellington
- Running lunchtime code club at local primary & intermediate school.

EDUCATION

BE (Hons) Software Engineering | Victoria University of Wellington

2019 - 2022

Wellington, NZ

- First Class Honours
- Specialising in AI/ML

PROJECTS

Genetic Algorithms for Community Detection in Social Networks | 📢 | 🌐

- Investigated existing Community detection algorithms, and identified issues
- Devloped and Implemented a new algorithm using GA utilizing Edien Vector centrality and local search to accurately and efficiently identify communities in social networks
- Tested across large datasets and published results

Exploratory Data Analysis and Manipulation | 🕠 | 🌐

- · Business and Data Understanding with seaborn
- Data Preparation
- ML model Design and Implementation with sklearn
- Model Evaluation and Improvement

Image Classification using CNN | •

- Data Analysis and Augmentation with pytorch
- Hyper Parameter Tuning
- Building MLP and CNN's with kieras and tensorflow
- Transfer and Ensemble Learning
- Evaluation and Reporting

Evolutionary Algorithms for Optimization, Computer Vision, and Machine Learning | 📢 | 🌐

- Cooperative Co-evolution Genetic Programming
- Estimation of Distribution Algorithm
- Evolution Strategies for Training Neural Networks
- Evolutionary Programming and Differential Evolution Algorithms
- Genetic Programming for Image Classification

Evolutionary Computing for Optimization Problems | 🜎 | 🏶

- used GA to solve a basic Knapsack problem and feature selection
- used GP with symbolic regression to solve the Rosenbrock and Griewank Problems
- NSGA-II to rank feature importance
- Particale Swarm Optimisation for feature selection

Checkout portfolio linked at the top for more info